David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, there she is!
Erin B: Yay.
Erin B: Hello!
Erin B: I'm a little bit horizontal.
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't have my! I don't have my headphones on.
Erin B: Okay, here's a cat.
Erin B: Hello, and then.
David Dobervich (he/him): Hello!
Erin B: Hello!
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. Hi cat.
David Dobervich (he/him): Ow.
Erin B: What have I done?
Erin B: Cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): How was backpacking.
Erin B: It was great. We did not see a rattlesnake.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, we.
Erin B: A guy who was living there for like months and taking up the best backpacking spot, and we did not make him.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. You didn't offer him any alcohol.
Erin B: No? Well, we did until we realized that he was, and he said, no. He
Erin B: said he would take food.
Erin B: We were like, no, we don't wanna enable that.
David Dobervich (he/him): Only whiskey.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay, what a sweet cat!
Erin B: Yeah. Isn't she beautiful?
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. Oh, your hold on! It's too hot. My sweater.
Erin B: So beautiful, thanks, so.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oof.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Noddy would love to visit your cat. Noddy's obsessed with cats.
Erin B: That'd be awesome.
Erin B: I mean, I don't know that they would.
Erin B: It would take probably a few hours.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, okay.
Erin B: Would it be actual interaction?
Erin B: They're pretty scaredy cats.
David Dobervich (he/him): My sister has, like an extremely old, extremely grumpy cat, that.
Erin B: Well.
David Dobervich (he/him): Hiss and clawed anybody except Julia and Stephen, and sometimes them even like that.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): More and more crotchety as time goes on.
Erin B: She just she just bit me cause I pet her wrong. But she does this really cute like
Erin B: it's it's just communicative. It's it's just.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, yeah, yeah, no. I like that. I know that kind of.
Erin B: Okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): How else is your breaking up? Wait! Your school is shutting down. Is that true?
Erin B: No, I guess not. I guess I just like was getting concerned that, like everybody was leaving all suddenly.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: So I don't know like how
Erin B: concerned to be, but I feel I should have a back.
David Dobervich (he/him): Them. Do you know why they're leaving.
Erin B: Oh, everybody's leaving for different reasons.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, okay.
Erin B: So it's not like one centralized thing.
David Dobervich (he/him): All right.
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, I guess that is like maybe a little bit less urgent. Then.
Erin B: Yeah, unless.
David Dobervich (he/him): Do you also want to leave.
Erin B: My commute is like 4 HA day.
David Dobervich (he/him): Whoa! What!
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, cause you go at the wrong time.
Erin B: Do? I.
David Dobervich (he/him): Wait. Is that true? 4 h.
Erin B: No, it's so, basically, I started taking the bus.
Erin B: It's 2 HA day.
David Dobervich (he/him): I see.
Erin B: Yeah, that's.
David Dobervich (he/him): Lot of hours on the bus.
Erin B: Yeah, well, it's biking and bus.
David Dobervich (he/him): No.
Erin B: Yeah, I don't know.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, you're too far north for me to commute you also. You were probably not awake at the time that I go.
Erin B: Yeah.
Erin B: Yeah. And I'm in Palo Alto.
Erin B: I have started so the bus I have to leave the house at 6 Am.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, that's like, it's like, not too different.
David Dobervich (he/him): Thank you.
David Dobervich (he/him): Actually.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: When do you go to work?
David Dobervich (he/him): I try and get out at 5, 30.
Erin B: Wow! Good job.
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, you know, I don't always achieve that, but that's the aim.
Erin B: Why?
David Dobervich (he/him): Let's see.
Erin B: Is, are you avoiding traffic.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. And like.
David Dobervich (he/him): my most productive time is in the morning. So I just like to maximize that time before school.
Erin B: Yeah, that makes sense.
David Dobervich (he/him): I'm at school right now. Well, there was a little bit of like physical classroom setup to do, but also Nadia is so sweet and wonderful, but I can't be interrupted at all. I'm very sensitive to sound like I put in earplugs, and then my headphones over my earplugs, and like I can't be interrupted at all
David Dobervich (he/him): interesting.
Erin B: I see?
Erin B: Yeah.
Erin B: that makes sense. Then what have you? What have you see? Work on some classroom setup? What else have you been working on?
David Dobervich (he/him): No God, just, just grading.
Erin B: Oh, my God!
David Dobervich (he/him): Greeting.
Erin B: I have so much grading to do.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I do a lot of thinking about how to lessen the load. And I just don't think it's possible unless I want to compromise.
Erin B: My future.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Assessment.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like I could just do multiple choice tests. But I can't.
Erin B: Yeah, yeah, I I didn't. I didn't.
Erin B: In previous years. I have not graded
Erin B: much, but this year I have, and like
Erin B: I do feel like I know the kids a lot better, and.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, that's true.
Erin B: And I think they're they're getting to do better stuff
Erin B: like they're like they're having to think more and being assessed on that. And yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): they're they're up. It doesn't, you know. I like the idea that I give them feedback, but it doesn't help if migrating sits for, like they did 2 projects
David Dobervich (he/him): and Precalc that I just didn't touch at all until break and.
Erin B: That doesn't.
David Dobervich (he/him): Help them.
David Dobervich (he/him): And actually, now
David Dobervich (he/him): all the grading is done. And so I'm thinking, you know, I'm not actually, gonna what I'm gonna do is, I'm gonna grade the projects for kids for whom it would make a great difference. And then for everybody else, I'm gonna say, Hey, it's not gonna make a great difference. But also, you know, like I hope you got a lot of learning out of it from, you know, teaching each other and all that, and if you want feedback, let me know, and I'll be happy to give you feedback on it.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, cause I don't. I don't other than defeat.
David Dobervich (he/him): feel like they put in all this effort, and nobody looked at it or cared about it.
Erin B: Yeah, I that I feel that for sure. Yeah, I
Erin B: it's stats I've been assigning like this packet.
Erin B: I basically just stole this curriculum. Mathematic.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, yeah, you told me about that.
Erin B: Yeah, I, really like it.
David Dobervich (he/him): Cool.
Erin B: And they give me homework and
Erin B: so I've been giving them that, and I give them the answer key also.
Erin B: Oh, my God!
Erin B: 8 10th check their homework. But
Erin B: I've been assigning, like every day, a packet.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Which I feel weird about. But there's only 3 days of class a week and
Erin B: so every time I grade, I just start with the most recent one, and there's some from like the beginning of the year that I haven't touched.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: But speak.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. You know, the last time when I was working with that new teacher
David Dobervich (he/him): who is very interested in like, How do you do an optimal grading policy.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, like, but like also like when you discount your own time.
Erin B: Right.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like I was really not into it.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know I have, like all these thoughts like.
David Dobervich (he/him): I have changed my grading policy
David Dobervich (he/him): kind of every year since I've started.
Erin B: -
David Dobervich (he/him): And I'm not sure the details of the grading policy really make that big a difference in what grade kids get.
David Dobervich (he/him): With the exception, with the exception that some kids are just really bad at multiple choice tests.
David Dobervich (he/him): So that's I mean, that's another reason why I can't only do that, because, like, I've definitely seen students who score great in every form of assessment, except that one.
Erin B: Wow!
Erin B: That's good to know. How many students do you have.
David Dobervich (he/him): This year many fewer, which is great, it would probably be unmanageable. I don't know what my!
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't know my exact overall number. I think it might be like 1 30.
David Dobervich (he/him): Maybe my classes are like about 30 to 32.
David Dobervich (he/him): Which is pretty small, like usually.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Be 34 to 38.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. And then my other thought about the great.
Erin B: I'm glad I started at in the email
Erin B: cool where the classes are smaller.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I mean, it's not such a big deal to like, teach a room full of a lot of people. But yeah, just the workload of the individual assessment is hard.
Erin B: Yeah, yeah, for sure.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like that was my other kind of thought. Was that more? It's very rare
David Dobervich (he/him): for a student's grade to change from week 6 to the end of the semester.
David Dobervich (he/him): There's a couple of students who get a grade that's not what they want, and they really like figure out how to fix their problems and fix them.
David Dobervich (he/him): There's a lot of other students who didn't get the grade they want and work much harder. But it doesn't do anything
David Dobervich (he/him): but yeah, like a lot of them. So I feel like there's gotta be something in there
David Dobervich (he/him): where, like, where, like, if students.
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't know what it would be. But like, yeah, like something where it's not. I'm regularly assessing everybody.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know. It would be like I could do some cheap, low resolution.
Erin B: Assessments.
David Dobervich (he/him): And then for students who like seem like they're moving a lot or.
Erin B: Good luck!
David Dobervich (he/him): Right on a borderline. I could do more expensive or like, like, you know, like, you know, saying
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): More frequent assessments. I don't. I don't know what it would look like.
Erin B: Yeah, what? What grades do you get?
David Dobervich (he/him): Huh!
Erin B: What range of grades do you get.
David Dobervich (he/him): In Precalc
David Dobervich (he/him): in Precalc before they did the retakes at the end of the semester. It was about a 3rd of them getting A's, about a 3rd getting B's, about a 3rd getting C's, and there were maybe like 2D's out of
David Dobervich (he/him): like 99.
Erin B: And the D's were. That was that like missing work? Or was that like not getting it.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's just like super lost.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Which is, you know, like really sad and unfortunate
David Dobervich (he/him): cause when you're so far behind. Yeah, you just can't keep up with any of the new stuff, because it builds on the old stuff.
Erin B: Right.
David Dobervich (he/him): And in computer science it tends to be
David Dobervich (he/him): much more. I don't know. Like, maybe 60%, a 40%. B,
David Dobervich (he/him): no, 6, 35% b 5% c.
Erin B: No.
David Dobervich (he/him): You still look so sleepy?
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I'm getting coffee.
David Dobervich (he/him): Nadia has been going to bed later. Later. I
David Dobervich (he/him): 9. I want to be in the bed at 9.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know, like we read out loud, and then we redo ourselves.
Erin B: Come on!
David Dobervich (he/him): And Nadia used to be in her bed at 8, which was great cause, like we could watch a couple of shows or whatever, and then read.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, and she was complaining because her cousin stays up late, and her best friend neighbor across the street stays up late, and she was like, Why do I have to go to bed? And we were sort of like, well, you don't have to go to bed.
David Dobervich (he/him): but also we we can't be available.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): But the problem is she, she
David Dobervich (he/him): can't eat the right amount at dinner, and so she gets hungry, you know, 6 times before bed.
David Dobervich (he/him): and she's like very capable of getting her own stuff except she's scared at night in the kitchen by herself. So so like last night at 9 30,
David Dobervich (he/him): I was, you know we were in the bed, and she came in and was like, I'm great.
David Dobervich (he/him): So we got out and.
Erin B: That's so. Cute.
David Dobervich (he/him): She ended up curling up at the foot of our bed for the whole night.
David Dobervich (he/him): Is, it is pretty sweet. She doesn't do it all the time. It would make me crazy if she did it all.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: On.
Erin B: Yeah, that sounds like a challenge.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's okay. I just.
Erin B: You know, as I get older.
Erin B: or maybe it's not me getting older. Maybe it's me becoming more like Mario, like Mario is super introverted.
Erin B: and I.
David Dobervich (he/him): Wouldn't have said that about myself before, but increasingly now, I just want to be by myself.
David Dobervich (he/him): I just need silence, and by myself.
Erin B: Nice.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. Well, sort of it's it's harder to manage. It was much. My life was much easier when I didn't have that requirement.
Erin B: Hmm, that's I mean, it can be, I mean, yeah, I guess you are
Erin B: a parent and a teacher, and a so a lot of
Erin B: so, and you have a lot of friends so like, there's a lot of people that want interaction.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, that's okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): So do you still want to talk about how to.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't know career stuff, I so I'm probably the wrong person to ask, like, we should sort of think about a little bit.
Erin B: So you you just like what you you studied and then did teaching. Is that what you did.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): So I did right. I did. Undergrad, unrelated to teaching.
Erin B: Right.
Erin B: And then, like you, I taught at a private school for a little while.
Erin B: Oh, okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): And then I thought, I in general support public school, and I would like to do that.
David Dobervich (he/him): And so yeah, figured out
David Dobervich (he/him): like you have to get the credential, and you have to go through the credentialing program.
Erin B: We don't know.
David Dobervich (he/him): Credentialing programs are like 2 years. And there's some that are one year, and part of the credentialing process requires classroom observations and
David Dobervich (he/him): maybe placement.
David Dobervich (he/him): So like we frequently get
David Dobervich (he/him): folks from like San Jose State, like I think San Jose State requires some number of observational hours before even entering the program.
David Dobervich (he/him): just so that you know what you're getting into before you before you go.
David Dobervich (he/him): And then, as part of the program, yeah, you do your student teaching where you get paired with a more experienced teacher.
David Dobervich (he/him): And there's like classwork. And the classwork is like
David Dobervich (he/him): adolescent developments. But then, also, like you know, like practical classroom management, or like assessment systems, or whatever and then you need to complete what's it called? It's called the
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't know what it's called. It's
David Dobervich (he/him): Some like portfolio of stuff that you submit to the California credentialing program and like the the credentialing program you're in like should oversee all of that.
David Dobervich (he/him): Basically, it's like you design a couple of lessons
David Dobervich (he/him): and you get videotaped doing them. And then you reflect afterwards.
David Dobervich (he/him): And it's sort of like. It doesn't. Really.
David Dobervich (he/him): It feels very stressful to be videotaped teaching. But it's you don't have to teach a perfect thing like everybody understands what teaching is like. So it's more, it's more like they want you, even if it goes very badly. They want to see that you have noticed the things that went badly and have ideas.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay?
David Dobervich (he/him): And that should be fine.
Erin B: Okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, and then even to get into the credentialing programs right? So you got to do the C best and the C set
David Dobervich (he/him): those 2 tests.
Erin B: We can do those.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. So the sea best. There's like, you know.
David Dobervich (he/him): there's like a like, maybe 6 dates a year that this maybe they're both offered. The sea best is very general.
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't really remember it. It wasn't something I studied for at all.
Erin B: Yeah.
Erin B: So standardized tests are usually pretty. Like
Erin B: I I have. I have whatever like abstract skill that makes them easier.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. The Csat.
Erin B: On earth.
David Dobervich (he/him): It may be worth brushing up on some areas. The csat is the like math specific one.
David Dobervich (he/him): And there's actually like 3 different levels. And I tried to do them all in the same sitting, which turned out to be a little bit tight on time, so.
Erin B: Thanks.
David Dobervich (he/him): I passed the 1st 2 and failed the 3rd one because I didn't complete it. And so then I did the 3rd one again on a different sitting, and that was fine.
David Dobervich (he/him): But it's like there's like one for algebra.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): There's 1 for geometry, and there's 1 for or like, no, maybe it's like, yeah, like algebra, one algebra, 2.
Erin B: It has.
David Dobervich (he/him): Geometry. And then there's 1 for calculus.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): probably worked with calculus for a lot longer than I did, though. So maybe you don't need to brush up. Maybe you're.
Erin B: I did learn it like 3 times. But hi, yeah.
Erin B: I never like. There are people who are like.
Erin B: it's just like in working memory, almost like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I am not one of those people. So yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): file, since you've integrated by hand.
Erin B: Yeah, absolutely, so.
David Dobervich (he/him): So you could like brush up on that a little bit. But yeah, they're not. They're not super hard tests.
Erin B: Okay.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like all, everything costs money. So you go to.
Erin B: Right.
David Dobervich (he/him): Pay for all the things.
Erin B: Right. I was like I was looking into like it kind of looked like there was a way to like have to pay less for the
Erin B: like, at least the like it. It seemed like, if you, if you manage to like
Erin B: like, you could potentially get a job at a public school without having gone through the whole program. If you were enrolled in a program, and then you could get paid while
Erin B: being observed.
David Dobervich (he/him): So, maybe.
Erin B: But yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, you always hear about stuff like that. But I don't know if it's tied to, you know, like high need in certain areas.
Erin B: Like when I was.
David Dobervich (he/him): When I was starting teaching. Yeah, that.
Erin B: Definitely.
David Dobervich (he/him): The case, I think, for math teachers, but only if you were in like a title, one school.
Erin B: Oh, okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): Or I don't. I don't know.
David Dobervich (he/him): Hmm!
David Dobervich (he/him): So yes, that does sound possible sometimes, but I think I don't think that's in general available. But.
Erin B: Just kind of
Erin B: just kinda like, take some time off and do a program is basically how it would be.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. And yeah, like, that's the other thing.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, I'll start saving up.
Erin B: Is like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Where you're teaching now.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know, it's clearly like really different than if you were gonna teach like in East Oakland.
Erin B: And so the rain.
David Dobervich (he/him): And I don't. You know, I've only ever taught at Fremont, so I don't have a good basis for comparison. But yeah, I know student populations are very, very different, I know.
David Dobervich (he/him): like the
David Dobervich (he/him): supportiveness level of admin is very different, and the support is supportiveness level of your colleagues can be very different.
David Dobervich (he/him): Whenever other teachers come to Fremont
David Dobervich (he/him): they pretty universally say, Wow! The the teaching staff here is extremely friendly and supportive of each other, which I've not experienced at other schools.
David Dobervich (he/him): which is like interesting to me, and makes me wonder how other schools are.
Erin B: Yeah. Do you feel like people are like you at Fremont, or are they.
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, I mean they're all very different from each other, and for me
Erin B: But in terms of like being cool.
Erin B: The other teachers.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I mean, there is a desire to collapse. So I'm I'm actually
David Dobervich (he/him): a little bit on the like kind of grumpy loner end. If you.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Believe it, because.
Erin B: That's surprising.
David Dobervich (he/him): The yeah. Well, it's because I have problems compromising
David Dobervich (he/him): my ideas like, I want to try the thing I want to try. And I'm like Super happy to work with other people if they're also interested in trying it, and if they don't want to try it, that's also fine with me, you know. But if there's an expectation that we're all gonna do the same thing, like I kind of want to just do my own thing. If I think it's going to be better for students like I don't.
Erin B: Yes.
David Dobervich (he/him): To me, I prioritize. Yeah, student learning above all else.
David Dobervich (he/him): But yeah, like, I think I think.
Erin B: That seems like what I would want from my colleagues.
David Dobervich (he/him): Some other teachers like. What it means for them to collaborate is, let's distribute the workload. So, like all.
Erin B: Design.
David Dobervich (he/him): This lesson. You design that lesson, and we'll both.
Erin B: No.
David Dobervich (he/him): But it's really hard for me.
Erin B: It was one of my.
David Dobervich (he/him): Think about the content really differently than I do.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): So that's why.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like it's, it's all a little bit awkward, because admin is never very explicit, like you need to be this way. And so it's all kind of these unspoken social expectations.
David Dobervich (he/him): And it's like hard for me to navigate that.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Because I don't want to be a jerk, but I also want to do things the way I want to do them.
Erin B: Yeah, I definitely can be that way where I'm like. No, I think this will work.
Erin B: Don't want to do this other thing.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like a lot of it, it's not about how it's about what
David Dobervich (he/him): you know. Like, I just don't think it's important to teach certain things.
David Dobervich (he/him): and I think it's really important to teach other things.
Erin B: What are you teaching now?
David Dobervich (he/him): Precoc honors for math.
Erin B: Precalc honors and computer science.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like when I look at Precalc honors, you know, I I have like about 6 different precalc textbooks that I sort of look at to draw inspiration from.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Good breakfast.
Erin B: Yep.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. And like, the more I look at them
David Dobervich (he/him): the more I can't believe that there aren't better materials available. Because, like, why? Why on earth would we drill students and being able to like graph the cotangent function like, why is that by itself?
Erin B: That's interesting, interesting or useful. Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): But like, that's what the whole curriculum is like. It's like, Here.
David Dobervich (he/him): here's a thing. Can you do this thing? We'll show you how to do the thing. So I feel really good about the curriculum I've developed because I.
Erin B: Who was.
David Dobervich (he/him): Mostly I mostly stick on the topics, but.
Erin B: Woo.
David Dobervich (he/him): But I try and either identify like, what's a useful thinking skill underneath this topic, or like, what does this topic connect to in the future. And like.
David Dobervich (he/him): yeah, bit is devoted towards those things so ideally, everything we do is going to be useful.
David Dobervich (he/him): Problem is that makes it
David Dobervich (he/him): so that if kids are having trouble and they have a tutor. The tutors like what in the world is happening like, I've.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Precalculus class like this before, and they're always like, where can we? Is there a textbook that you use? And the sad truth is, no, because all those textbooks are dumb.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know. But like, if you're having trouble, you just want to get into college.
David Dobervich (he/him): you don't want your teachers. Idealism about math to prevent.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay, it's college.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, that that's.
Erin B: I have a colleague at Kahila who definitely like he teaches Precalc, and he has
Erin B: the similar sort of like.
David Dobervich (he/him): But that's dumb to make kids memorize this stuff. I understand that
David Dobervich (he/him): I gotta share resources with that guy.
Erin B: Yeah, that I think I'm not sure.
Erin B: Yeah. And I, you might also clash with each other. But you're definitely clashing with the other people.
David Dobervich (he/him): I mean I.
Erin B: His name is.
David Dobervich (he/him): Clash with him unless we were required to do the same thing, like, I'm always interested in hearing other people's ideas.
Erin B: Yeah, he doesn't pressure other people to do anything. So.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, what's his name?
Erin B: Jeff Holcomb, I can connect you guys.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I mean, you know, he might not have time or interest, but.
Erin B: Oh, he probably does.
David Dobervich (he/him): Be nice there. Okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): I mean, if anything. Yeah, I would just love to hear if he has resources that he doesn't think are stupid.
Erin B: Yeah, he usually does stuff on Desmos
Erin B: and he does have a book that he's having the kids go through
Erin B: and they're often complaining.
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, it's hard to say about that.
Erin B: Biz.
Erin B: and a lot of the complaints are like, but I want to jump through hoops, and you are making me learn math.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, that's true.
Erin B: Hi!
Erin B: Look at this little cutie!
David Dobervich (he/him): So, yeah, you could just like.
David Dobervich (he/him): yeah, just start researching. Like, when do the tests happen? And like, you could just take the tests. And then I think the scores are just there in your record, and you could just like slowly go through
David Dobervich (he/him): genius.
Erin B: Yeah, make sense.
David Dobervich (he/him): No.
Erin B: Open up!
David Dobervich (he/him): You know what is worth looking into? I don't know.
David Dobervich (he/him): It is almost certainly the case that
David Dobervich (he/him): there's some credentialing program where, like, if you have been teaching private school. You don't have to do.
Erin B: Yeah, there are those. But the you have to. You have to have like 5 full years, or something like that.
David Dobervich (he/him): Thank you.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): What are you at now? 2.
Erin B: Probably 2 cause. I did
Erin B: well, definitely 2 by the end of this year, because I was part time
Erin B: 2 years. So I think that
Erin B: gives me one year, and then this is my 3rd year. So I think that would be 2 years, maybe.
Erin B: So. Yeah, one and a half. Now.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, it would be cool, you know. It'd be cool if you could teach at a place that was like on the East Bay.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: But I don't know. I was talking to somebody that like. There's no benefits or anything. I don't know if that's the case in sunnyvale.
David Dobervich (he/him): At private schools.
Erin B: At public schools.
David Dobervich (he/him): Wait! What do you mean?
Erin B: Apparently the Union like bargained away that a while back.
David Dobervich (he/him): What?
Erin B: In favor of salaries, so they just don't have health insurance or something.
David Dobervich (he/him): That seems much worse.
David Dobervich (he/him): That was the wrong move. Union.
Erin B: Yeah. And I, I was like, I was trying to like, understand it. It seems like there it it's
Erin B: they definitely bargained away some benefits like 20 years ago and.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Now we are.
David Dobervich (he/him): I guess it. Maybe.
Erin B: Consequences.
David Dobervich (he/him): Maybe 20 years ago. It made sense. I don't know.
Erin B: It probably did. But then, like the prices of the health insurance.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, yeah, it's not true in our district that's cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, it's going to be hard to get into our districts.
Erin B: Oh, cool! Good to know!
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: What happened?
David Dobervich (he/him): I mean, just like it's too expensive for families to move to our houses, and so.
Erin B: It's just.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like all old older couples.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Or like young working professionals that don't want kids.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's a Fremont is the only one that's not contracting like I forget
David Dobervich (he/him): I forget which high school, but one of the high schools, like the projections are that like 6 or 8 years from now, there's gonna be like 300 students
David Dobervich (he/him): from like 8.
Erin B: Oh!
David Dobervich (he/him): Or something right, like everybody's just going.
David Dobervich (he/him): And so they're talking about like rezoning, you know, and parents are like going berserk about rezoning, because, like you can't send the rabble to our high school, you know, like we gotta.
Erin B: And that's on.
David Dobervich (he/him): Prices are based on our high test scores like, you can't let those kids into our high schools. So there's like all this chaos happening. I'm mostly staying out of it.
Erin B: Yeah. Are you wanting to stay at Fremont.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I like Fremont. I mean, the commute's not the best, but it's not the worst.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I like Vermont.
Erin B: Do you drive every day.
David Dobervich (he/him): I do?
Erin B: How's traffic? On the way back.
David Dobervich (he/him): Not good.
Erin B: Hmm.
David Dobervich (he/him): like last year. I didn't teach the last blocks of the day, and so I was able to get out.
Erin B: That kind of.
David Dobervich (he/him): Early. And that was okay. This year I do. And so I leave like around 4.
Erin B: It was like, 45 min.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Snow 2 h, though.
Erin B: Yeah. Well, I I mean, it's it's it's only
Erin B: like 50 min to an hour on the way home if I drive. But
Erin B: I hit most motorcyclist on the freeway on the way to work last year. And he's okay. But like.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's good.
Erin B: It was terrifying. And then I was like, Wow, I need to do better. And then I rear ended a Va bus.
David Dobervich (he/him): Wow!
Erin B: Several months ago, and I was like, you know what
Erin B: I need to get myself off the road, especially if it's like a route that
Erin B: is like I'm getting desensitized to from doing it.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, yeah.
Erin B: You know.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's true.
Erin B: So
Erin B: I'm super lucky. There is a free that goes from Fremont Bart. Station to like 15 min away from my school.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, yeah, cause like Palo alto transit hub. It's right there.
Erin B: Yeah, exactly.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, cool.
Erin B: Yeah, so it. But the thing is, the bus is like, I guess Stanford wanted to do the like free, like the Stanford has one of those buses that, like the tech companies have where they're like, here, our people get the special bus system except that they get government funding. And so I'm guessing that that's why they can't do that. And so it's a free bus for the whole community.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, that's so nice!
Erin B: That is not advertised very much and has no labels on it. But you just get on.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's really funny.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): So how did you find out about it?
Erin B: Hi googled and it didn't show up immediately. Like, basically
Erin B: it is, it is online. It's just.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Like Google is aware of that bus line and does like suggest it. It's just like there's no labels on it. And like
Erin B: And like, it's a little hard to tell from Stanford's website unless you like, dig into it like this is actually free. You don't have to pay for it.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: You're allowed to get on it. If you're not affiliated with Stanford.
David Dobervich (he/him): I was. Gonna say.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, if I know people like you want to put the sentences the second sentence in your second paragraph, and no one will ever know.
Erin B: Yeah, exactly.
Erin B: Yeah.
Erin B: Yeah. Reading is hard. Hi, Ella? Oh, Hi, Zoe, we went to Sespi
Erin B: and we left the kitties with our old housemate, and they're friends now.
David Dobervich (he/him): Sweet.
Erin B: Yeah, they like are way better at respecting each other's space than before. They went on this trip together.
David Dobervich (he/him): Great.
David Dobervich (he/him): How's Danny's program?
Erin B: That that one truly is imploding.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh! What!
Erin B: I don't. Oh, oh, it's a whole thing!
David Dobervich (he/him): That's that, was it. Through Berkeley.
Erin B: Oh, no. Okay, so.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I'm way behind here. Last I knew he was gonna do some data science boot camp.
Erin B: Okay. So the data science boot camp that was through Berkeley is actually just this, like kind of shoddy
Erin B: training thing that is using Berk like it paid for using Berkeley's name. But they're not affiliated with Berkeley.
David Dobervich (he/him): You could even do that. What the heck Berkeley.
Erin B: Yeah. So that's kind of shady.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: And so
Erin B: A friend of Danny's from one of the like meetup groups was like, Hey, I think this might be one of these like
Erin B: companies that does this sort of like shady
Erin B: practice thing like you could do it. But there's probably better things, and like people aren't necessarily going to perceive this as
Erin B: like a Berkeley degree.
David Dobervich (he/him): Right.
Erin B: So then.
David Dobervich (he/him): Danny was mostly doing it to try and get contacts, anyway.
Erin B: Yeah, that's true.
Erin B: So he ended up going with a different one.
Erin B: That you like one of those you only have to pay after you get a job ones.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: So so he's in one of those right now. He's doing App Academy, which our friend had done like 10 years ago, and that had worked out really well for her.
Erin B: But it is very different now.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: Yeah.
Erin B: So he's doing App Academy. It's almost over.
Erin B: So he's learning database management and website development.
Erin B: which he's having a lot of fun with that.
David Dobervich (he/him): What's his? What? How do you say it? What's what's his stack? What do you say? Do you know? Saying like, what are the technologies?
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh,
Erin B: No. Js.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay. Hi, cat.
Erin B: Some python.
Erin B: I think they do a lot of different
David Dobervich (he/him): I see.
Erin B: Sequel things.
Erin B: not sure which one. These are things that I don't really know, and I think can't remember. It's react, or if it's something else, but it's 1 of those like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Do you? Do you know different stacks for.
David Dobervich (he/him): Sort of, I mean, not not really, but sort of where do you?
David Dobervich (he/him): Still a ruby on rails, Guy.
Erin B: Oh, yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like rails, has come a long way, apparently in the last 15 years, he was saying, like.
Erin B: Really.
David Dobervich (he/him): Of rails is just so. Such a joy to work in.
Erin B: Oh, that's cool!
David Dobervich (he/him): The last, like major website I made, which was like 12 years ago, anyway, else
David Dobervich (he/him): but now I you know I haven't used ruby or rails since then.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, I don't remember anything about the middle.
Erin B: I am in my Cs class at the end, because a lot of the seniors graduate well, actually, it's not even because of that. I just at the end of the class. I have them make a portfolio website.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): So I usually just have them do like, super basic. HTML, yeah.
Erin B: Then I had last year be like, here's a python library that's like way easier to interact with. And I was like, Oh, okay, cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): What was library?
Erin B: And I have already forgotten.
Erin B: Let's look at this kid.
David Dobervich (he/him): Was it flask?
Erin B: No, but it. I think it used something similar.
David Dobervich (he/him): I mean, that's more. I think Flask is more of a framework, but.
Erin B: Yeah, it may have used flash.
Erin B: Let me look it up. It actually was pretty cool. Now, the the issue was like he was
Erin B: depending on them to host.
Erin B: But I now since that class I did buy a
Erin B: server, so I'm like renting a server.
David Dobervich (he/him): Cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know, if you don't have any back end stuff like Github will host.
Erin B: Right? Yeah.
Erin B: Github pages. Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, exactly.
Erin B: Streamlit
Erin B: streamlet.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, cool!
Erin B: But I think he's moved on because I don't see his portfolio up there anymore.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay, I don't want to make an app, though. I want to make just a website.
David Dobervich (he/him): although people use the word app for all kinds of things now so.
Erin B: Oh, yeah, no. Streamline streamlit is. You can just make a website.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
David Dobervich (he/him): I'm looking at it. Oh, yeah, I want to do this.
Erin B: Really.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, hey? You and Danny were doing some like like auto. Generate random problems for Matt.
Erin B: Yeah, it was so cool. I mean.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, I'm not.
Erin B: No, I'm on board.
David Dobervich (he/him): Don't want to do it now.
Erin B: You really? Oh, my God! So it's it's.
David Dobervich (he/him): Just for freak out.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, it's so much work. Tell me more about your experience.
Erin B: But it's so cool, so I got it to generate
Erin B: and let me see if I can pull it up.
David Dobervich (he/him): Do yours do so, you're generating problems. Do you also generate? Is, do they have like short answer inputs? Or is it multiple choice or no answers at all. Just questions.
Erin B: So it's specifically stats, calculations.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay. Oh, right? Okay.
Erin B: So yeah, I'm pulling it up right now. So the kinds of questions are like.
Erin B: in like in region, a 80% of dogs have spots in a sample of 100 dogs from region B, 60% of dogs have spots. A researcher wants to know if the proportion of dogs that have spots in region B is different from in region A at a significance level of alpha is 0 point 0 5. Compute and interpret the appropriate test. Statistic.
David Dobervich (he/him): I see. Okay.
Erin B: And
Erin B: so it's a lot of like, calculate and interpret the appropriate test statistic. And it doesn't grade it. It just creates the question. Because, like kids can answer in in various formats,
David Dobervich (he/him): Right.
Erin B: And then I also want to create, like the histogram below, show that shows the heights of a hundred dogs in region. A in centimeters describe the distribution.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know how to generate different histograms that
David Dobervich (he/him): are random, but also have the property you want. Yeah, that's.
Erin B: Yeah, yeah. Well, it doesn't even necessarily have to have the property I want. I just have to know what the property is.
Erin B: and then like dropbox plot of the same data. Stuff like that. And so right now, the only I don't have the graph aspect of it done
Erin B: but but like, and I only have for this one like setup right. I only have z scores
Erin B: for a proportion, or sorry ZZ test for a proportion.
Erin B: maybe also Z intervals for the proportion.
David Dobervich (he/him): Are you doing this in Javascript Python?
Erin B: Python.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: And ultimately, like, I want to be able to give the data like when I say, like in region, a 80% of dogs have spots in a sample of 100 dogs from Region B, 60% have spots like, I would like to deliver that information
Erin B: also, just as like a bar plot.
Erin B: But what what ended up coming out of this is like.
Erin B: so we can basically.
Erin B: So given a set of calculation fields. So yeah, let me see how I
Erin B: structured this, because I really like it.
Erin B: Sorry, the thing that came out of it is it? Asked questions that I would have never thought of asking.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: But yes, a kid could answer that question. And so it's like questions that I've never seen that format. I've never.
Erin B: Had that situation where, like, here's the data you're given, and here's what you're supposed to figure out. I was like, oh, I never even occurred to me that if you had this data, you could figure out this conclusion. Yeah, so that's what I liked about doing this. Is it created structure of problems in terms of like what algebra you had to do, that I hadn't seen before.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, yeah, that's cool. I'm trying to do a quite different kind of thing.
Erin B: Okay, cool. What are you trying to do?
David Dobervich (he/him): I'm trying. I just want like, basic. So so like precoc honors, part of what the honors means is that we don't spend a lot of time drilling stuff that students who are good at like picking up on patterns can get pretty quick.
David Dobervich (he/him): But there are students who are taking the course, who are not that student, and they won't practice.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): so yeah, it's just like generating practice problems. But I want it to be where. So there's like 2 things that are different than just regular worksheets.
David Dobervich (he/him): one is. I want to be able to some extent to control the mix of
David Dobervich (he/him): like what gets included in the practice. For example.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know, like sine of 2 x or something.
David Dobervich (he/him): Students always think that that 2 refers to the period.
David Dobervich (he/him): And so it took us a long time to be like, oh, why is that not the period? Okay? 2. Pi over the frequency is the period. And then we started using like sinusoids to model like oscillating motion or like rotating motion.
David Dobervich (he/him): And so then we'd have problems where it was like this thing is like rotating 5 times a second.
David Dobervich (he/him): and so they would do like 2 pi divided by 5. But that doesn't really make sense.
David Dobervich (he/him): So it turns out, yeah, there's like 4 or 5 different ways of describing a ro like a constant rotational rate.
David Dobervich (he/him): Where you know you have to like, think about, what do the words mean?
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, about what the words mean? It's not too hard to get to the answer. But it's not like
David Dobervich (he/him): there's
David Dobervich (he/him): fixed formula you can just use, and, like all the practice that I have, all the practice that exists has, like segmented it out so far that it's like for this type of problem. Do this for this type.
Erin B: Right here.
David Dobervich (he/him): So I want to make my own practice that like mixes it together. And it's like, don't think, what type is it? Think, what are the words describing, and then you should have a mental, and there's like I want them to reason in terms of mental models. So I give them the mental model, and then use that to answer the question depending on what's being asked.
Erin B: So yeah, the the auto practice I'm generating needs to be a little bit different.
Erin B: That sounds way easier.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yes.
Erin B: Way.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yes, I it is problem. So you don't need to do any nlp, which is cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yes, that's true.
David Dobervich (he/him): I am a little bit. Think so right now, I'm doing multiple choice answers. I kind of like the idea that
David Dobervich (he/him): for other things we're gonna have short answer.
David Dobervich (he/him): And then you have, like the mild difficulty of
David Dobervich (he/him): how are they gonna enter an equation in a box.
Erin B: Maybe.
David Dobervich (he/him): So.
David Dobervich (he/him): And then what if they enter an equation? That's algebraically. You know the same.
Erin B: Can I? Tell you my idea of how I was gonna grade these
Erin B: so it would involve human grading.
Erin B: But I wanted to sort of set it up for the human grader.
Erin B: Do, are are you? Do you need it to be like auto feedback, like immediate feedback?
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't need it to be anything.
Erin B: Cause you could publish an answer key of like. Here's an example. Answer.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: And then
Erin B: also like good. But so what I was thinking is so it produces homework and an answer key.
Erin B: And basically, this is my vision, and I don't know if it would.
Erin B: I don't know if it would even be useful, but I was envisioning what if I like, put the fit like. I print out the homework for the kids, so wasting trees, and then scan the homework that they give me.
Erin B: And there's little like QR. Codes and stuff within their homework.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: So that once I scan their homework that gets put into a Pdf on my computer and then goes into the grading interface that way. And then in the grading interface I can filter by question or by student, and the program will show me, like the students, answer and the correct answer side by side, and then I can choose from like radio buttons, like full credit, partial credit or no credit.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, I see!
Erin B: Lets me comment and then and a dropdown menu lets me choose.
David Dobervich (he/him): So is it like the? Is it like the homework that gets auto generated, the pages divided into like quarters or.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Thing.
David Dobervich (he/him): QR. Code, like in one spot in each of the 6th cool. That's a cool idea.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, I've thought about doing things like this before using. QR. Codes is a good idea. I've just been doing it, like.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, like, I know, like the resolution of the scan. And so I'll just like draw dividing lines.
Erin B: Yeah, that could work.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I like that.
Erin B: The QR. Code is nice, because then you don't have to
Erin B: like you can lose information about like
Erin B: like whose homework this is. Like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Good.
Erin B: Or
David Dobervich (he/him): Like which which assignment you're scanning? And you can regain that information from the QR. Code later.
David Dobervich (he/him): because it encodes all.
Erin B: Gave this to this student like I could put their name on the home.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's a great idea.
Erin B: Worth, yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): I'm gonna do this.
Erin B: Really.
David Dobervich (he/him): This is a great idea. Yes, I mean not immediately, but.
Erin B: Right someday.
David Dobervich (he/him): Time permitting.
Erin B: Yeah.
Erin B: this is also great cause. Then you can do tests this way and do different versions of the test for each student.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: And then
Erin B: like it, would it? Would it would give them different questions from each other, while keeping the like general style of question the same.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, now, I like this plan.
David Dobervich (he/him): All right.
Erin B: But making that interface of like.
David Dobervich (he/him): You, you scan the Pdf. And then the the the script like reads the.
Erin B: Pdf. And parses all of the questions and like maps them to the QR. Code and everything like, and then gives you like a little like. Here's your like grading interface. That sounds
Erin B: like work, but like relatively straightforward work.
David Dobervich (he/him): How wait! Have you done this? Or you're just thinking about this.
Erin B: I have not done that. So what I have done so far is
Erin B: for Z tests. Generate questions that all have to do with dogs. That give different. So what we did is, how did we? How do we structure this? We basically like named the different.
Erin B: So there's like desiderata, which is what you're asking the student. Oh, here we go.
Erin B: So here's the data structures.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: So we're only working with confidence intervals and null hypothesis, significance. Testing the data types that we're doing this for will be proportions means differences, and Chi squared. But for now it's only for proportions.
Erin B: The data structures are. So you give. So there's you don't necessarily give this. But
Erin B: for every question there's a context. So that's a lot of nlp, so like generic categories, animals, people, plants, specific categories within the generic categories, features for each generic category units for each feature, grouping relative clauses for each generic category and a researcher identifier. So that's the context.
David Dobervich (he/him): Makes sense.
Erin B: Then you've got your calculations. So this is where you generate, like the data, any graphs, any statistics, and any conclusions from those statistics like, there's a significant difference between these groups or whatever
Erin B: those calculations
Erin B: and the context exist for every question. But I don't necessarily give all of that information to the students. So then there's the question. So for any set, so so for for any context and calculation set, there's a set of Givens. So somehow keep track of the minimal sets of givens and how much extraneous information there is. So we're basically we're deciding. I'm going to give the student like this amount of information.
Erin B: And then for any set of givens, there's a sequence of demonstrata.
Erin B: So each demonstratum has an accessibility based on the Givens and the previous demonstrata.
Erin B: So basically like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Of how many Derek?
Erin B: Yeah, so
Erin B: number of algebraic steps, or like a statement that like you can't get to that demonstratum from those givens, because sometimes, like the Ap tests like, Oh, you can't, you can't determine this. They cannot be given. So yeah, so so the context and calculations are like creating the world. And then the question is the Givens and the demonstrata, and then you can search
Erin B: through the Givens in the demonstrada to find like, Hey, I want a question with like this number of algebraic steps, where the demonstrata is like interpreting as a Z statistic.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, cool.
Erin B: And then you can use, like Nlp, maybe even an Llm. To generate the question, text and answer from a.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I was wondering about that second thing. If you thought about that.
Erin B: The Llm.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Yeah, I think it can be done with like super dumb like old school. Nlp, and then you don't have to worry about the Llm. Making shit up.
Erin B: But the Llm. Could potentially be nice for cleaning stuff up, if you really like. Trained it to not make shit up and really only like edit. The Grammar.
David Dobervich (he/him): I don't know if I I don't know if I gave you this example.
David Dobervich (he/him): I think this is from like a year or 2 ago, you know, as a previous generation of models.
David Dobervich (he/him): But yeah, I gave up my problem. And I was like, you know, write me a new version of this problem with like a different surprising context. And it wrote more or less the exact. It was like a problem involving a restaurant. And I forgot what all.
David Dobervich (he/him): and it gave me more or less the exact same problem, and I was reading through it and thinking kind of like what the heck, and then the very last sentence was. And the surprising context is Colon. The restaurant is in a submarine underwater, and it's completely dark inside. It's funny enough that I put it on my test, anyway.
Erin B: That's really cute.
David Dobervich (he/him): Twist at the end. You know they're they're getting a lot better, though I definitely use them to generate new contacts.
Erin B: I used it to make my syllabus because I was like, Hey, can you help me? So that, like a student who doesn't do the homework can still pass the class like if.
David Dobervich (he/him): They do. Well, that's interesting.
Erin B: You know, and it so it helps me with like different styles of students like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, that's great, interesting.
David Dobervich (he/him): or somebody who has like super test anxiety and can't succeed on a test can still get an a like.
David Dobervich (he/him): yeah, I don't have a good system for this yet I liked. Here's here's a new thing I've been toying with that I liked. I read somewhere about. Oh, shit! I never gave you that book.
David Dobervich (he/him): Aaron. I'm that book that I've been saving for you.
Erin B: Oh, speaking of which, do you still do the making a like yearly book thing cause that was so cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, no, it was never yearly. It was more like.
Erin B: Periodically.
David Dobervich (he/him): There is. Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): The last one fade was the recipe book. Did you get.
Erin B: No, it's got a recipe book.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh!
Erin B: Yeah, I took a lot of time.
Erin B: Huh? Now I do.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay, all right, shoot. I'll give you a copy of the book.
Erin B: Thank you.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's a that one is like 4 years old now, though.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, like our 2020 book.
Erin B: Yeah, I mean, like you, you have a very busy life. So like, it's a big like deal to create a book.
Erin B: and I admit that I have not read all of what you have already given me.
David Dobervich (he/him): Good.
Erin B: But I I find it just like so.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: Comforting and beautiful, and I really really like it. So thank you.
David Dobervich (he/him): Thanks.
David Dobervich (he/him): I have no memory of having given.
Erin B: Anything.
David Dobervich (he/him): But that's great.
Erin B: I have the like perception. One and blueprints of fancy.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, is the perception? One. The the animals, one.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, yeah, okay.
Erin B: I really like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, yeah, okay, cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah. Well, so anyway, I have a, I have a teaching book I've been meaning to give you, for I think a whole year now. Maybe.
Erin B: Nice.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, here's my question, though.
David Dobervich (he/him): What's going to happen to you next summer? What does your summer look like.
Erin B: I think I'll probably be here.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: Why?
David Dobervich (he/him): Do you have any interest in having some kind of like like Co accountability co-work structure.
Erin B: Yeah, and I don't know what the cadence would be.
Erin B: I'm not a very reliable person. So I would recommend having
Erin B: a fallback plan. If I say.
David Dobervich (he/him): What the Co. Accountability is supposed to be about.
Erin B: I know, I know.
David Dobervich (he/him): To me.
Erin B: What I know, but I.
David Dobervich (he/him): Glare at you.
Erin B: That would help.
David Dobervich (he/him): I can't! I can't do it.
Erin B: Yeah. So we'd be doing a fallback plan for to make sure that you you make it through.
David Dobervich (he/him): What if the accountability structure is that like they're like the meeting happens like in your apartment.
Erin B: Oh!
David Dobervich (he/him): Because then it's like from this app.
Erin B: Hour to this.
David Dobervich (he/him): Hour.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Going to show up.
Erin B: Wait! That's so good.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay, I mean, you don't have to. But what I'm saying.
David Dobervich (he/him): I thought my thought was some number of times a week like you.
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, you can work on whatever you want. But my thought.
Erin B: You have this programming.
David Dobervich (he/him): I'll do it.
Erin B: Will interrupt you, but no human children who will interrupt you.
David Dobervich (he/him): Love to be interrupted by Cat
David Dobervich (he/him): thought. He's gonna be at a a camp, anyway.
Erin B: What do you need to be comfortable working in a space.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh!
Erin B: A table, a power outlet. Do you need a monitor.
David Dobervich (he/him): Probably a second monitor. I can second monitor, though. That's fine.
Erin B: Really.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah.
Erin B: Okay, yeah, I.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like. If you don't mind me leaving one, I could just leave it with you.
Erin B: Yeah, absolutely you could potentially. Yeah, let's
Erin B: Oh, my God! My friend gave me this desk.
David Dobervich (he/him): All right.
Erin B: I'm sitting here. Okay, great. This is the rest for the summer.
David Dobervich (he/him): Because my thought was.
Erin B: With that.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know, I want to try and really build out my programming thing. And you could do your program.
Erin B: Excellent.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know, and like we could say, Hi.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Chat for 10 min, and then we could go into the zone.
David Dobervich (he/him): Work focused way for a couple of hours, you know, but then we could kind of show off whatever it was that we did at the.
Erin B: Yeah, yeah, if it happens here. It's more likely to work.
David Dobervich (he/him): All right.
David Dobervich (he/him): Cool.
Erin B: Thank you. But you yeah, that 10 min of getting started might be me getting out of bed.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay, that's fine.
Erin B: Okay, that's great.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's totally acceptable.
Erin B: Thank you.
David Dobervich (he/him): And we don't know Danny could be doing anything at that time.
Erin B: Yeah, oh, yeah, so.
David Dobervich (he/him): So.
Erin B: Is imploding. So, so app. Academy is imploding, so.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, right!
Erin B: It turns out there are. So they they used to be a lot more, and they've been like
Erin B: they've been falling apart for a long time.
Erin B: So like Danny can see in the materials that, like there used to be people who like really knew their stuff, and since then those people have all left or been laid off, or whatever and so who's left is like people who are just like they kind of understand what people have left for them.
David Dobervich (he/him): Right.
Erin B: And there used to be a lot of support in finding a job after this, and they paired that down a ton. So there's like one person for like 50 people, and they like check in like a couple of minutes a week, or something. But it used to be a lot more like hands on, like one on one support.
Erin B: And so now there looks like some lawsuits going. Maybe I I'm not sure what for, for, like false advertising, or for like something and Danny's is like the last cohort of this, like everyone, is getting laid off at the end of this cohort.
David Dobervich (he/him): So but so that pretends.
Erin B: Yeah, but everyone like they have a discord panel, and, like everyone requests to work with Danny whenever there's like a group project.
David Dobervich (he/him): All right.
Erin B: They all like go to him for office hours as much as they go to like the tas for the course so like. If any of these people get a job. I hope that they bring Danny with that
Erin B: know.
Erin B: Also a bunch of the staff of Af. Academy just got laid off, too, so maybe they would bring Danny somewhere with them. So that's.
David Dobervich (he/him): In some ways I don't know. In some ways this might be the best thing.
David Dobervich (he/him): Cause like this was Danny's original plan was to get contacts.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, right?
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, having everybody recognizes intrinsic excellence.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): And then bring them along. That's smart. Yeah.
Erin B: That's the hope. I mean, that was always the hope. It's just like if if the app Academy is so like the worry is, if nobody
Erin B: gets a job after this right?
Erin B: You need a program where the people who are graduating like do, in fact, get jobs.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, yeah. The rails guy I know just got laid off again
David Dobervich (he/him): every time he gets laid off. He says, you know, it was like a problem with my boss. And Mario was like, you know you get. This is the last time just saying
David Dobervich (he/him): problem with your boss every time you're the common denominator here he was like, I get it. I know I know
David Dobervich (he/him): it sounds like.
Erin B: Thank you.
David Dobervich (he/him): It sounds like
David Dobervich (he/him): bosses often ask for feedback, and he gives. He gives feedback, and they don't want to hear feedback. And then he also.
David Dobervich (he/him): he also wants to improve the code base rather than continue to perpetuate the bad practices.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, Danny, they don't always wanna.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Want that.
Erin B: Yeah, that has definitely been a clash. That Danny has experienced.
David Dobervich (he/him): Don't wanna rock the boat.
Erin B: Yeah, he also, I don't know if he told you that he applied to like just like this security guard, like Job, like last year.
Erin B: and they were like, what? Why do you want this job? And he said the money.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, they?
David Dobervich (he/him): And they said that was the wrong answer, and he was, Do you want me to lie? And they were like, Yes.
David Dobervich (he/him): what is the right? Answer?
Erin B: I don't know. I don't know.
David Dobervich (he/him): I can't imagine. I can't imagine how I would, how I would even lie. I mean, I can, I guess, but it's so transparently false.
Erin B: Yeah, I I think you could say like, Oh, I'm I'm excited. For, like the.
Erin B: you know, like having a a regular schedule. I'm like, very good at like being out of place at a time, and like this seems like it's not a predictable schedule, and I love that, and I'm very reliable, you know, like, you know.
Erin B: yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like, why would you?
David Dobervich (he/him): I would be so excited. Yeah, exactly.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's different, though.
Erin B: Well.
David Dobervich (he/him): That was the question.
Erin B: So definitely.
David Dobervich (he/him): Should ask that question, yeah.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like
David Dobervich (he/him): I was. Yeah, I was thinking, like I used to be, you know, a cat burglar and a black hat. And you know, I just thought I'd try the other side for a little while.
David Dobervich (he/him): That's probably the wrong answer. Also.
Erin B: Yeah, I think that was that was Danny's perception, also that the woman some like story about how this was like.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: His grandma's dying wish, or something.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, like, my apartment got broken into repeatedly. And so I spent a long time really researching how to secure a facility.
David Dobervich (he/him): And now it's my passion.
Erin B: Yeah, yeah, I would love also, like, as we're going into
Erin B: next year, like over the summer, like talking about grading system stuff, too. I think.
David Dobervich (he/him): Danny could have given a good and true answer to that question.
David Dobervich (he/him): I think it's Danny is interested in the puzzle of How do you secure something because it's difficult.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): You know it's okay. I don't, anyway.
Erin B: I think his job was. Oh, oh, also, like I, I like interacting with people. And I know that I'm really good at like de escalating a situation. That's another one. Yeah.
Erin B: Yeah. I really.
Erin B: I do like what has happened with like, a few times this year, a student has been like
Erin B: really distressed about their grade.
Erin B: And then they've been like, what can I do? And I've been like, look at the syllabus. Here's the breakdown you're not actually in a bad place right now, and this is how you get to the place where you want to be.
Erin B: and it's been going really well, I I took your advice, and I
Erin B: like a long time ago you had said about retakes that if there's not a grade in the grade book of the original score that they got. They believe that they're better than they are.
David Dobervich (he/him): M.
Erin B: So I always keep the original score in the grade book.
Erin B: but I give. I have 3 grades for each assessment. I have a reflection grade where they fill out a Google form and if they fill it out at all, they get a hundred percent
Erin B: and a retake grade. And the original grade, and they're equally weighted.
David Dobervich (he/him): Okay.
Erin B: And that's been going really? Well.
David Dobervich (he/him): No.
Erin B: And a lot of them just don't fill out the reflection.
David Dobervich (he/him): We don't have a lot of department time. We get like an hour as in a department every month. But this year the overarching theme that our Department chose to think about
David Dobervich (he/him): was what did we call it? I forgot what the phrase was. But it's about grading practices.
David Dobervich (he/him): There was a phrase which was like your grading practice, or like your your grading policies, should be so transparent that every student knows exactly what grade they have, and why and what they can do to improve it.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like that, you know, I was thinking about that.
Erin B: What does that mean?
David Dobervich (he/him): Well, that's part of what we're unpacking. Cause. Yeah, it turns out
David Dobervich (he/him): we've uncovered a couple of meanings in there.
David Dobervich (he/him): So like, right now, our grading practices
David Dobervich (he/him): like on a test. For example.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, the test has previously stated topics. The test will be on these topics.
David Dobervich (he/him): and there's like certain things we're looking for
David Dobervich (he/him): students to be able to know or do.
David Dobervich (he/him): And they're like bullet points. And so then the test is always like, Okay, if you got it. Then that's full credit. If you were missing.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, here's like bullet points for major deductions. Here's bullet points for minor deductions. And so it's all like very clearly laid out. And then you get that grading rubric. And so if a student's like, why did I get this grade? It's very obvious. So I got this grade because I got these 2 bullet points. But I missed this bullet point. But in my mind that's not maybe the most helpful thing like that. That way of explaining why you got the grade you got is designed to make your grades defensible.
Erin B: Yeah. Totally.
David Dobervich (he/him): But it's maybe not the most helpful thing for students.
Erin B: Yeah. And and sorry. Do you predict? Do you publish the rubric with the
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, assignment when you give it to them. Okay, because it can be.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, like, there are students who like totally understand precalculus, but they have so many algebra, 2 like algebra mistakes.
David Dobervich (he/him): then it doesn't matter how well they understand the precalculus. They can't get any really
David Dobervich (he/him): right, because they constantly simplify stuff wrong. And so that right? I feel like the bullet points don't really reveal like, what do you need to do to get better? You need to go back and drill these common algebra. 2 errors.
Erin B: Right.
David Dobervich (he/him): Like or like.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's really common for students who have a B who want an A to
David Dobervich (he/him): like have the wrong mindset like they're they're still stuck on, you know. I see this. I do that. I'm gonna memorize some rules.
David Dobervich (he/him): And my my tests are designed so that you can get a B by doing that, but you can't.
Erin B: That's good.
David Dobervich (he/him): May by doing that. And I tell students that all the time I'm like you can't.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Here's and then and then I also say, here's what you need to be able to do to get an a. But again, like the grading practice doesn't make it like when they're looking at their tests. It's not like, Oh.
Erin B: That's.
David Dobervich (he/him): He said. That's why.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): So that that's what I'm gonna be thinking about. I'm gonna be thinking about.
David Dobervich (he/him): How can I make my grades communicate like, what category of student. Am I right now? And what do I need to do to level up?
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, that's cool.
David Dobervich (he/him): I like to phrase it in terms of leveling up, because.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): Students always want the checklist.
David Dobervich (he/him): Checklist, you know, if you're gonna level up.
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, you gotta do stuff, but it's not. It might be different amounts of stuff for different people.
David Dobervich (he/him): And there's no timeline for leveling up. Some people could level up, maybe pretty fast. Some people may may take a while to level up. So
David Dobervich (he/him): you know, I want to try. And yeah.
Erin B: It's really cool.
Erin B: Yeah, I'm definitely not at the point in my like career where I feel like I can even assess
Erin B: students knowledge really.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's hard.
Erin B: Yeah, I'm literally just giving them a grade on like, did you do the stuff? And I'm trying to like, make the stuff be stuff that like will result in knowledge. But I'm very much like grading like, did you do the class and not do you understand the material.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I am constantly surprised.
David Dobervich (he/him): Here's here's here's the thing I do that constantly surprises me. It's usually during warm ups.
David Dobervich (he/him): All think, what are we studying right now? Okay, what's a what's a really really basic question I could ask about these concepts that students should be able to answer pretty quick if they know what's happening.
Erin B: Yeah.
David Dobervich (he/him): And like that, reveals all kinds of very interesting misconceptions.
David Dobervich (he/him): Because I'm not trying to have them apply it. I'm not trying to have them solve a problem. It's just it's conceptual. And it's just like, do you know what's happening at all? And the answer very frequently is, no, not at all.
Erin B: Right? So that's.
David Dobervich (he/him): Really changed a lot about what I do all the time.
David Dobervich (he/him): I'll make up a throwaway, warm up question that's supposed to take like 30 seconds, and then it turns out nobody knows what's happening, and that like changes. How I teach everything. So that's.
Erin B: Yeah, that's definitely.
David Dobervich (he/him): Been an ongoing practice of mine.
Erin B: That's good. Oh, yeah, yeah. How long are your classes?
David Dobervich (he/him): 90 min.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, block days. And then on Mondays they're 50, 45.
Erin B: 45.
David Dobervich (he/him): On Mondays. Yeah.
Erin B: Wow.
Erin B: I'm gonna use the fact that I have you on the phone, too.
Erin B: Energize me to do a menial task on my computer.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, I'm gonna need to go. Probably pre, I respect that.
David Dobervich (he/him): I didn't realize how much time had passed.
Erin B: Thank you so much for hanging. I am excited to look into like
Erin B: actually transitioning to public school, and thanks for just like talking through your memory of what's involved in that, and.
David Dobervich (he/him): Sure.
Erin B: I'm really excited to nerd out about problem sets this summer.
David Dobervich (he/him): Yeah, me, too. I'm always excited to hang out with both of you.
Erin B: Done.
David Dobervich (he/him): In regards to Danny.
Erin B: Oh, Danny, he's getting food right now. You can at least say, Hi, sorry. Do you have a meeting? You're going to.
David Dobervich (he/him): No, but I don't have lunch, and I have to drive home.
David Dobervich (he/him): Oh, yeah, okay.
Erin B: No.
David Dobervich (he/him): It was my intention to leave here about nowish.
Erin B: Oh, okay, cool.
Erin B: Oh, I don't. Oh, there he is here.
David Dobervich (he/him): Hey? Hi!
David Dobervich (he/him): I heard your program's imploding, but everybody loves you.
Erin B: Yeah, that's a pretty good summary.
David Dobervich (he/him): How was the hike.
Erin B: The hike was amazing.
Erin B: We got to watch the sunrise a couple of times from from the hot tub.
David Dobervich (he/him): From the hot tub. Yeah. Nice.
Erin B: From the natural springs.
David Dobervich (he/him): How far away do you camp from the hot tub.
Erin B: One a couple of nights we were like 20 feet away, 10 feet away, somewhere in that range.
David Dobervich (he/him): That sounds like the right? Yeah, cause I wouldn't wanna sunrise.
David Dobervich (he/him): It's great. But then you I gotta like, get to the hot tub before the sun rises, that seems.
Erin B: Yeah. 1. 1 night we were that close the other night. We were actually a bit further away. Now that I'm thinking about it. That night we were
Erin B: we got there. It was super dark.
Erin B: The campsites that we came across that were clearly campsites had people in them, and
Erin B: we decided to keep going does have to go home. I want him.
David Dobervich (he/him): So you know, I was just like, Hi, yeah.
Erin B: We'll we'll talk more later.
David Dobervich (he/him): What in Aaron?
Erin B: Bye, bye, David, thank you. Bye.